in the top our news here at six o'clock
an age-old dream
becoming a reality a local inventor has
discovered a way
hear this to use water to run your car
it's a major breakthrough that will no
doubt make motorists happy and as ralph
robinson explains the pentagon
is also showing lots of interest in this
project
water has always been considered a
precious commodity but stan meyer's
invention may make it even more valuable
he has developed what's called a water
fuel fill it has taken the place of his
old gas tank
the water fuel cell breaks down water
molecules into oxygen and hydrogen
the hydrogen is used to run his dune
buggy i don't care if you use rain water
well water city water ocean water
if you don't have any fresh water go
ahead and use snow
if you don't have any snow available to
you they use salt water because there's
no adverse effect to the fuel cell
meyer started working on this project
four years ago he's not a scientist he
isn't even a chemist
in fact he never graduated from college
myers was determined he says to design
something to protect this country from
oil embargoes
and we have calculated that if we take
the dune buggy from los angeles to new
york
we would roughly use 22 gallons of water
the pentagon flew of lieutenant colonel
in last week to look at meyer's
invention
there's talk of possibly using it in the
star wars defense program and to run
army tanks
myers is currently perfecting a water
fuel cell for cars it will cost about
fifteen hundred dollars
he says it won't need any maintenance
and you won't have to replace it
it'll be at least two years before the
fuel system goes into mass production
the data happens we won the fuel
industry hates
but i'll put a smile on the face of
those who hadn't seen one time or
another
fill her up i'm all problems as you can
see
many patents have already been received
and many more are forthcoming car that
runs on water instead of gasoline can it
be true
well inventor stanley meyer made an
announcement today in colorado springs
he says he's come up with a device that
will hook up to any engine and allow it
to run on good old h2o
news 13's kurt gough tonight on the
possible impact of the water fuel cell
stanley meyer says the answer to
dependence on foreign oil
lies all around us in sea water
tap water and rain water any kind of h2o
he says
can power just about every type of
engine how
with the water fuel cell it fits in the
palm of his hand but it could
revolutionize the world
talking about a pollution free totally
new source of energy the voltage
disassociation of water
the fuel cell converts water into a gas
hydrogen
oxygen which is released in the form of
thermo-explosive energy
so the water fuel injector simply
replaces the spark plug
we hook it to a hydrogen computer system
which regulates and meters the flow
going into the injector
it processes the water in such a way to
release its thermal explosive energy
the man who invented an engine that can
run on water
says he's been offered a billion dollars
in cash by oil producing countries to
sell his patent
so far he hasn't sold environmental
specialist jan porter talked to the
inventor
who thinks that the u.s auto industry
could produce cars that run on water now
if they wanted to our industrial base of
the world is based on the utilization
stan meyer has a car that runs on water
and that's drawing crowds at this year's
extraordinary science conference in
colorado springs myers has developed
what is called the water fuel cell
injector
the injector breaks down the water
molecule into hydrogen and oxygen
and the hydrogen is what powers the car
basically all we do is replace
the spark plug and replace it with the
water fuel cell injectors you see right
here
we simply feed ordinary non-processed
water or process water in here
and as the water goes into the injector
uh it
hits a very high pulse voltage frequency
which instantly converted into thermal
explosive energy and as a result we can
run this car
down the road on water buyers invention
was introduced in britain earlier this
month
and now the brits have followed him here
we recently took a scientific delegation
to witness stan's work to really
evaluate it and came back saying
this is one of the most important
inventions of the century
for 15 years now has been fighting to
get his inventions taken seriously
most inventors have to be a loner you
have to be
somewhat thick skinned and don't rely on
other people
to support you because they will not
more times than not
uh intervention is really stolen from
the inventors even in my
prior development of high technology
i've had
patents taken from me i learned from the
school of hard knocks to be very
cautious
ma has always stood out against the
crowd he has no formal qualifications as
a scientist
because he didn't wait to graduate from
high school leaving early to go straight
into research at the high powered
battelle institute
in his native ohio now he works
full-time as a private inventor
guilty advice and potentially
revolutionary implications
there's nothing starting about a machine
that can extract the hydrogen from water
what is highly unusual is that it should
do so with ordinary tap water
conventional method is called
electrolysis
maya has turned that process on its head
and like electrolysis
his device doesn't use up large amounts
of electric current
or does it produce an enormous amount of
waste heat
for 20 years he has been refining a
method to fracture water
produces vast amounts of hydrogen on
demand
this is not his latest apparatus he was
unwilling to let us point a camera at
that
this is the simple device he used to
convince a reluctant patent office
but his revolutionary concept actually
works
[Music]
alloy rods acting as electrodes are
housed in a perspective container that's
filled with water
normal mains voltage is fed in through a
transformer but critically
there is virtually no current consumed
less than half an amp
result is dramatic hydrogen pours off
with a flick of a switch
meyer claims the key is his electronics
which pulses electricity
rapidly across the rods and up to 20 000
cycles per second
in a way that's not readily apparent
this process transforms the equation
whereas in conventional electrolysis
three times as much energy is consumed
as is produced in the form of hydrogen
fuel in mars apparatus the reverse is
true
it appears to produce several hundred
percent more energy
than it consumes